Welcome to the series on complete Go programming language.
Go programming language, also known as Golang,
is already being loved by startups.
And also, this language is already in production
for giants like Google and Dropbox and many others.
Now, this brings this programming language
already into a unique position where startups are loving it,
as well as it is already present in giants.
This is an amazing programming language,
which you are going to love.
Hey there, everyone.
My name is Hitesh,
and I'll be your instructor for this entire series
on the Golang.
I've been writing code for a while,
and I know how to teach that code as well.
My specialty is to turn the toughest topic
in the easiest one so that learning becomes absolute fun.
In this series of Go programming language,
we are going to get started with absolute basics.
First, we're gonna clear up
that how Go programming language is different
or similar to other programming language.
Once we are done with that,
we are going to learn how to install Golang
onto your local system,
and we'll fire up our VS code
to write our very first program.
Once we are done with that,
the obvious next step is to understand
how the Golang work, its lexer,
how we declare variables, conditional loops and functions.
Once we have good practice of these basics,
then we are going to move into the web side
of a programming language.
We're going to learn about the structs,
and we are going to explore how we can create
as well as decode JSON.
We're going to learn about how to make web request,
how to accept the response from the web request,
and during this, JSON is going to help us a lot.
After that, we are going to learn
that how we can build APIs
using whatever the knowledge we have gained so far.
Once we are done with the building of the basic APIs,
then in the next module,
we are going to learn that how we can inject MongoDB
and can create a full-fledged REST API
using Golang and MongoDB.
Once we are done with all of that,
then we are going to move into the most amazing section
of the Go programming language,
which is how to fire up goroutines,
sync packages, mutex, and channels.
This entire series is jam-packed with fun,
a lot of code that we're going to write together,
as well as together,
we're going to go ahead and read the documentation
to find out behind-the-scene details
of the Go programming language.
I know reading documentation is not that much fun,
but don't you worry, I'll take care of that,
and I'll teach you enough of the basics
so that documentation doesn't scare you off.
After watching this series,
you are going to realize
that Golang is not just any another programming language.
It solves very unique issues,
and it is one of the most ideal programming language
if you're working into the cloud infrastructure.
Channels, mutex, goroutines, sync packages, pointers,
there is so much in this language
and is having a fresh take
on how to deal up with the things.
Learning Golang in this present era
is going to take you a step ahead
into your journey of programming.
So obviously, the next question is
that how can you access this series
and what this series is going to cost you?
Now, if you are a member of pro.learncodeonline.in,
then this entire series will be available to you
entirely on the day one.
But don't you worry, if you are not a member of that,
that is also fine.
You can still access this series.
A lot of you gave me a lot of love and support
by subscribing to pro.learncodeonline,
and as a saying thank you or as a gesture,
I just kept this entire series
absolutely for free for YouTube.
So every single day,
we are going to post up one video a day,
just like YouTube loves it, one video a day.
Every single day on 5 p.m.,
you are going to see one video a day.
So you can just spend five to 10 minutes in a day,
and within just no time,
you will be absolutely mastering Golang.
And by the way, just quick side note,
we don't upload on Saturdays
because I go live on Saturday,
so you won't be seeing videos on Saturday.
Rest on all of the days,
you are going to see one video a day sharp at 5 p.m.
I will already pre-upload everything
and will mark them as a scheduled video
so that you can see all of that.
So yes, summing it up,
yes, this series is going to be free.
You are going to see one video a day
if you want to watch it on YouTube.
If you are already a Pro member,
you can just access it all in one go.
And yes, of course, a big shout out
to all the people who have supported me
on pro.learncodeonline,
and because of you guys,
this series was made possible,
and because of your love and support,
this series is absolutely free for everyone.
I am super excited to share all the journey
that I have seen so far while working in the project,
digging up into the documentation, everything.
And this is going to be one fantastic series.
I am hoping that all of you will show up eventually,
and let's go ahead and get started
with Go programming language.
And yeah, by the way, a side note,
the music is going to be only in this video.
The rest of the videos are not going to get
the ending music that some of you are a big fan of.
(upbeat music)
♪ I'm not with the moves ♪
♪ Don't wanna meditate ♪
♪ Girl, with you it's hard ♪
♪ Fill in the blanks ♪
♪ Text me back ♪
♪ Throw me a kiss ♪
♪ Instead of them tricks ♪
♪ Don't make it hard ♪
♪ I wanna celebrate ♪
♪ You know ♪