[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hey there, everyone.
My name is Hitesh, and I'll be your guide
for this entire series.
So welcome to the series on Go Lang,
a series that's going to start from absolute scratch,
absolute basics, and it's going to go with a lot of in-depth
and behind the scenes of Go language.
Now, Go is truly an amazing, powerful programming language,
which is very impressive and modernly designed.
And one thing that's especially amazing about the Go
is whether you are a programmer in the very initial phase
of writing the code, or you're somebody
who is way more advanced, have written years and years
of code, you're going to still love this.
And this is already a code, a language, which
is already in the production.
And people are just loving it.
And you will know the reason that why they are loving it
by the end of this series.
So without further ado, let's go ahead and get started
and begin our official journey to become Gophers.
Yeah, we call people who write code as Gophers,
just like there are Pythonistas.
There is-- we got Gophers.
So Go is also termed as the next-gen programming language.
Some people also go to the length
and say that if C would have been designed
in the present era, this would be it.
This is how powerful the Go language is.
And you're going to very soon understand
that a lot of languages bring up the features over the time.
And some of these languages don't
come up to utilize the true power of the cloud
infrastructure.
And that is one of the reasons why
Golang is getting so much of popularity.
And this language is already in production.
So I'll bring up a little bit of the theory
in the initial videos.
Then we're going to just go ahead, write some code.
We'll read some documentation and have fun
in writing code in the Golang.
So let me go ahead and officially get started
and answer some of your questions,
because these are the common ones which
appears as you go initially in the language itself.
First, is this language compiled?
Or is it interpreted?
Or is it somewhat in between?
In case you don't know, just a quick sidebar.
The languages can be compiled.
Like, every code is being read at first.
And then an output file is being created, like an exe.
And then you just run that.
It's really fast.
Or it can be interpreted, just like JavaScript code
runs line by line.
Or it can be somewhat in between, just like Java does.
Now, what is the difference between the Golang and Java
and other languages is that Golang is compiled.
In the languages which are in between, like Java,
it just doesn't get compiled.
It just gives you some of the intermediate binaries.
And it expects that any machine who is going to run this code
should have this virtual machine installed, or also known as JVM.
Not the case with the Golang.
Golang actually handles that way differently.
It just compiles everything.
And runtime is baked into the final product.
So as long as you have just Go installed,
you don't need any JVM or any kind of thing.
And you just go ahead and run that.
Now, this is what we do that.
Now, not only that, Golang actually gives you some set of tools
that you can utilize.
And we're going to talk about them way end of this course,
that how these tools can actually be utilized.
And you're going to take so much advantage of it.
Because there is a lot of control which just Golang-widge takes
from the operating system and literally gives it to you,
especially in the cases of threads.
We're going to talk about them way later on.
But this is all about it.
Executables are exported at the compile time.
And Go gives you whole options to produce the compiled output
or the final executables for Windows, for Linux, and for Mac.
And there are options for that.
And definitely, we'll be doing that.
That is so much fun to do.
Another thing is what.
This is really important.
What and where I can use Golang?
What can I build with it?
Where can I use it?
And the good thing is that Golang is already in production.
And that is the biggest advantage
that any language has ever seen.
This language is already moving into the Dropbox, a whole lot
of Google ecosystem, and a whole lot of cloud infrastructure.
A lot of companies are using it.
And they are shrinking up their machines
that they were previously managing.
If they were managing five or six machines,
now they are shrinking it down to just two machines or one
machine.
And later on, I'm going to give you more examples of that.
And that is the beauty about the Golang.
It is already in production.
And that's why people love it so much.
Moving on.
Now, this is one of the mistakes that I would like to just warn
you up here.
Please don't bring in any baggage with this language.
And what does I mean by that baggage?
Surely, if you have coded in any other programming language,
that experience always helps you,
no matter what the language is.
But bringing up those mindset that, you know,
this language doesn't have a switch and case
statement or something else--
no, it doesn't have.
And it shouldn't have, because the mindset
with this language's design is really different.
And it took me a long time to finally understand that.
And I'll show you and share this experience with you as well.
But please don't bring any baggage.
This language misses out a lot of features
that you are kind of familiar in writing.
But you don't need them in this language.
This is entirely a different language.
And surely, if you have written any code in C, Java, Python,
JavaScript, Pascal, anything, it's
surely going to help you, because the syntax of most
programming languages, common things like creating
variables, constant, loops, and conditionals
are very much similar.
Minor differences here and there,
which I'm going to talk about.
So please don't bring any baggage.
And rest, I'll take care of that.
Moving on.
Is this language object-oriented?
Kind of yes and no.
According to the true definition of object-oriented programming
language, you should have classes.
You should have object.
We don't have classes in Golang.
We have structs, which is kind of an alternative for classes.
We also don't have any kind of overloading.
Like, we don't have operator overloading.
We don't have method overloading.
Some people call that as overriding as well.
No, we don't have any of that thing.
What you see is directly on the code itself.
And you can understand that.
That's one of the principles I'll discuss later on with you,
that Golang is designed with simplicity in mind,
that what you see on the code, you can just
decide what's about to happen by looking at the code.
There is no prerequisite.
You don't need to understand that whether this language
supports overriding or not.
That is not the case.
This is not how this language is designed.
So there are differences here, which I'm going to eventually
tell you all that.
But I know these are common questions
you want to know as you start a journey for a programming
language.
So I want to just clear them up right in the very first video.
Moving on.
What is missing in this language?
In fact, a lot.
A lot is missing in this language,
but not in the terms that this language is lagging.
This language is missing a whole lot of things,
especially like a lot of people point that out.
The try-catch is missing.
And a lot of people even write articles
that how you can mimic the try and catch.
Honest answer, you should never.
This language is not designed like the other languages,
so there is no try-catch.
And you will never need that.
And that's what it is missing.
A lot of time, you're going to see that there are no try-catch.
And also, you're going to see a lexer is
doing a lot of work for you.
For example, don't worry.
I'll explain this as we write code.
You don't write semicolons in this language.
And I'm going to walk you through with the documentation
as well, that the documentation says you should be writing it.
But actually, the longer goal is to understand
that why this lexer is there and what help it is providing.
For example, even if you don't write semicolon,
it's not going to give you any error,
because lexer actually provides you all of that.
I know this is going quite a lot in depth of it.
And we are already going in depth of it.
And we haven't yet started to write any of the code.
But I'm pretty sure this has answered
a couple of your questions, gave you a good mindset
to get started with the Golang.
And that's all I want to you from this very first video.
In the next video, we're going to see the home page of Golang.
And we're going to just go ahead and see
what are the tools and everything that we're
going to require to write all of these things.
And from there, we're going to get started.
Let's go ahead and catch up in the next video.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[BLANK_AUDIO]